Oh, hey, you guys
I couldn't get
a reservation
for the night
of my birthday
so we'll have to do dinner
Thursday night instead.
Thursday?
But that's Halloween.
So?
It's just spooky, that's all.
Uh... So, is Mike
coming to dinner?
No. It's my first birthday
with a boyfriend
and he has to work.
I'd get mad at him, but I think
it's a little too soon
to show my true colors.
I would make
the reservation for five
because one of us has
to stay home and watch Emma.
Which one of us
should go to dinner?
Oh, Rachel!
Uh, actually,
I was thinking
maybe both of
us could go.
Oh, yay.
Thanks, I'll put a lot
of extra thought
into your gift.
All right, so, great,
we can all go now.
That is fun. Hey!
You know what?
We all haven't been together
the six of us,
in such a long time.
What are you talking about?
We're all together right now.
Uh, Mon, Chandler's not here.
Oh, dear God.
♪ So no one told you
life was gonna be this way ♪
♪ Your job's a joke,
you're broke ♪
♪ Your love life's D.O.A. ♪
♪ It's like you're always
stuck in second gear ♪
♪ When it hasn't been
your day, your week ♪
♪ Your month,
or even your year ♪
♪ But I'll be there for you ♪
♪ 'Cause you're there
for me, too. ♪
Hello, everyone.
It's nice to see
our team together
for the first time.
Now, before we get started,
are there any questions?
Yes. Ken, is it?
That's right.
Is it true that the reason
you're here in Tulsa
is that you fell asleep
in a meeting and took the job
without realizing
what you were saying yes to?
( laughs )
Well, don't believe
everything you hear, Ken
but, yeah, that's true.
All right
let's get started
by taking a look
at last quarter's figures.
Uh, Claudia,
aren't you supposed
to blow smoke up
the boss's ass?
I'm sorry, does the
smoke bother you?
No. No, no, no.
I smoked for years, then I quit.
Right now, I can't remember why.
You're not allowed to smoke
in this office, though, right?
Yes, in Oklahoma it's legal
to smoke in offices
with 15 people or less.
Would you like one?
All right, look--
I don't smoke anymore
but if the rest of you want to
light up, go ahead. It's fine.
So you all smoke, then?
It's almost rude
that I'm not smoking.
Well, that's
not true.
If you don't want to smoke...
Ken, please!
No, I can't smoke.
If I smoke, my wife
would kill me.
I'm sorry, but isn't your wife
back in New York?
I've always liked you, Ken.
( knocking )
Trick or treat?
Hey.
Ooh, a treat it is.
Wow. So glad I changed.
I almost wore my threadbare robe
that can't contain my breasts .
This is not
what I'm wearing.
I'm ovulating and Chandler's
going to be home any minute
so I thought we would
"try" before dinner.
Oh... Oh, wait!
You guys won't be late
for my dinner, will you?
Believe me, Chandler and I
have not seen each other
in over a week.
We'll probably be
the first ones there.
Okay, see you there.
Happy humping.
Hey.
Ooh. Wow, somebody
smoked out here?
Oh, my God, don't people know
you're not allowed to
smoke in public spaces?
Actually, in Oklahoma,
smoking is legal
in all common areas in offices
with fewer than 15 people.
Oh. You smoked.
No. I just happen
to know a lot of trivia
about smoking
in different states.
For example, in Hawaii
cigarettes are called
"lei-lana-lukus."
Oh, Chandler, you
stink of cigarettes.
Do you think Monica's
going to be able to smell it?
Are you kidding? That woman
has the nose of a bloodhound
and the breasts of
a Greek goddess.
Pheebs?
I'm going to go.
Okay. Something
to cover the smell.
Oven cleaner.
Unscented.
Welcome home.
I've missed you.
You want to join me
in the bedroom?
No, thanks, I'm good.
Okay.
So, you want to play
it that way, do you?
Right. You know what?
Actually, I just got
off a plane so I'm feeling
kind of gross. Maybe I
should just take a shower.
You don't need a shower.
All right, the truth is...
I soiled myself
during some turbulence.
What do I smell?
I smell smoke.
( gasps ) Did you smoke?
Yes, but I just had one.
Two.
Two tiny cigarettes--
okay, five.
A pack. Two pac... a carton.
Three big, fat
cartons in two days!
But it's over.
I've made a decision and I'm
not going to smoke anymore.
Well, those are for you.
All right, well, we'll just see
you when you get here. Bye.
Oh, that was my mom.
She's stuck in
terrible traffic.
Okay, well, that
is now the third sign
that I should not leave Emma.
Well, what are the other two?
Well, let's see--
the first one is
I don't want to,
and the second one--
I'm not going.
Rach
I know this
is the first time
we're leaving the baby,
and, hey, I know
how hard it is for you, but
everything's going to be fine.
I mean, my mom is
going to be with her.
She's great with kids.
She is?
Yeah.
What about Monica?
Hey, you only hear
Monica's side of that.
Okay? That little
fatso was a terror.
I just don't think I can do it.
Rach, you know what?
You can and you should.
Really, it'll
be good for you.
In fact, you know what?
Why don't you go ahead
to the restaurant and I
will wait for my mom and
then I'll meet you there.
No, no, really. You should go.
Just go. Go, really,
the world is your oyster.
Kick up your heels.
Paint the town red.
You need to learn
some new slang.
I'm serious. Come on,
you should go.
Uh-uh-uh.
Just go.
Oh!
No, no. You know what?
You're not getting
back in there.
The baby's fine, now scram.
Yeah, tell your story walking.
I was just going to say
that I left my keys.
Oh.
Holy moley, are we
in a pickle now.
Where is everyone?
They're 40 minutes late.
I know...
I'm starving.
I knew we were
coming here tonight.
I ate nothing all day.
How about me?
I only had one lunch today.
So, are we expecting
the rest of our party shortly?
Yes, they are
expected presently.
Yeah. Their arrival
is in the offing.
Right. Well, we do have
a table for two available.
Perhaps you'd be more
comfortable...
No, they're coming.
We're waiting right here.
Joseph.
One needn't worry--
they shan't be long.
It's just that we do
have some large parties
waiting.
Oh, one really does have a stick
up one's ass, doesn't one?
How can you smoke
in this day and age?
Have you not seen
that ad? Huh?
Where the little kid walks
through Grandpa? It's chilling.
I messed up. It was a meeting.
Everybody was smoking.
So what? Don't you
have any willpower?
Willpower? I've
watched home movies
of you eating Ding-Dongs
without taking the tinfoil off.
You said that was sexy!
Okay, look.
Can we just drop this?
I'm not going
to smoke again.
That's right.
Because I forbid you
to smoke again.
You forbid me?
Mm-hmm.
You know, I've flown a long way
to see my loving wife.
Is she here, by the way?
Oh, Chandler,
don't joke with me, okay?
I'm very, very upset right now.
Oh. Would you
say this is the most
upset you could be?
I think so.
Well, then I
might as well...
do this.
Not really sure what to do now.
Well, I'll tell you
what we're going to do.
We're already late
for Phoebe's birthday dinner.
So you're going to put out
that cigarette.
We're going to put this fight
on hold, and go have sex.
Fine!
What?
Sex! This is
the last day I'm ovulating
and if we don't do it now
then we're going to have
to wait till next month!
You're serious.
Oh, yeah.
All right, fine.
I'll do it. But no talking.
( gasps ) And no cuddling.
And no kissing your neck.
Oh, good, I hate it
when you do that.
And lots of kissing your neck.
Okay, the super's not home,
but, you know what?
My mom is going
to be here in a minute
and she has the key.
I can't wait that long.
You have to do something.
Knock that door down.
I would, but
I bruise like a peach.
Besides, you know,
everything's going to be fine.
The baby's sleeping.
What if she jumped out
of the bassinet?
Can't hold her own head up,
but, yeah, jumped.
Oh, my God! I left
the water running.
Rach, you did not
leave the water running.
Please, just pull yourself
together, okay?
Did I leave the stove on?
You haven't cooked
since 1996.
Is the window open?
Because if a window's open
a bird could fly in there.
Oh, my God, you know what?
I think you're right.
I think... you know what?
Listen.
Listen, a pigeon, no,
no, wait, no, no.
An eagle flew in
landed on the stove
and caught fire.
The baby, seeing this,
jumps across the apartment
to the mighty bird's aid.
The eagle, however, misconstrues
this as an act of aggression
and grabs the baby in its talon.
Meanwhile, the faucet
fills the apartment
with water.
Baby and bird
still ablaze, are locked
in a death grip
swirling around the whirlpool
that fills the apartment.
Boy are you going to be sorry
if that's true.
Hello.
Hi.
It's been an hour.
The maitre d' has asked
if you'd be willing
to reconsider switching
to a smaller table.
Maybe we should
just eat now.
You can't order
until the entire
party has arrived.
Restaurant policy.
Well, how about this?
Another table leaves, right?
But there's still some food
left on their plates.
Okay? What's the restaurant's
policy about people eating that?
It's frowned upon.
But it happens.
All right, I got to
go to the bathroom.
No, you can't go.
No, no, no. I can't
hold this table on my own.
If they ask me
to move, I'll cave.
Well, if you ask me
to stay, I'll pee.
Okay.
Good evening, miss.
Miss.
Okay, fine, I'll move.
All right, you don't
have to manhandle me.
Where?
Okay.
Thank you.
Well.
Finally, you guys made it.
Pheebs, who
the hell... ah!
Oh... spend
more time
with the tie.
That'll make a baby.
Look, I can't do this.
I can't make love to you
while we're fighting this way.
Oh, sure--
now you're Mr. Sensitivity.
But when you wanted to have sex
right after
my uncle's funeral...
That was a celebration of life!
All right, look--
I'm not going to do this.
All right-- is this really
the way you want
our baby to be conceived?
No, you're right.
Yeah, we shouldn't do it
like this.
( sighs deeply )
For what it's worth, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have come down on
you so hard about the smoking.
So you had
a few cigarettes.
It's not the end of the world.
Really?
Yeah.
You are incredible.
And listen, I'm not
going to smoke again.
And if I do,
I promise--
I will hide it
so much better from you.
Do you want to?
Yeah, let's
celebrate life!
Okay.
Whoa, God!
Oh, thank God
you're okay.
Oh, I'm so sorry
we left you.
Mommy will never
leave you again.
Never, ever,
ever again.
( sighs )
Great, so let's
get going.
Oh, no, I mean it.
After what just happened,
I'm never leaving her again.
I understand.
Separation is hard.
One time, I was about
to leave Ross
to go to
the beauty parlor
and he got so upset
he took off
all his clothes
tucked his willy
between his legs
and cried out
"Mommy, I'm a girl.
Take me with you."
Somehow, over time
it got easier
to be apart from you.
Ahh...
You are welcome.
You know what?
Let's not talk.
What?
I am still so mad at you
for smoking.
But you said you forgave me.
It was just a couple
of cigarettes-- no big deal.
Blah-blah-a-blah-blah-blah-
blah-blah.
I just said that
because I was ovulating
and you said
you wouldn't have sex with me
if we were fighting.
You tricked me
to get me into bed?
That's right.
I got mine.
I feel so used.
Well, I guess
they're not coming.
Want to just order?
Thank you.
Waiter!
This is going to go fast
so try to keep up.
Risotto with the shaved truffles
and the roasted rib steak
with golden chanterelles
and the bordelaise sauce
unless any of that stuff
I just said means "snails."
It does not.
Tomato tart
and which of the pastas
would you recommend?
Oh, well, they're both...
Both it is. Thank you.
Oh, can I make
a special request?
Can you bring everything
as soon as it's ready?
Appetizers, entrees,
we don't care...
Hi... hi...
Oh...
I'll just wait
to put your order in.
You guys are over an hour late.
What happened to you two?
So sorry.
We got locked out
of the apartment...
That's a great story.
Can I eat it?
And then Rachel
wasn't sure
she could leave
the baby.
Yeah, it wasn't easy,
but it's your birthday
and I did what
I had to do.
And that's Judy
over there at the bar
with Emma?
But honey, this
is for the best.
This way I'm not
distracted
worrying about Emma,
how she's doing at home.
And I'm going to be
completely here
with you...
And, oh, she spit up.
What?
She spit up.
Judy, she spit...
Judy, look alive,
Judy!
Thanks.
Whoo, everything
looks delicious.
What should I have?
What should
I have?
Never hit a woman,
never hit a woman...
I know what you mean.
This looks incredible.
Ross bruises like a peach.
He bruises like a peach.
Okay, I'll have
the fig salad
and the duck.
Yeah, I'll have
the soup and the salmon.
And remember, whatever
comes up first, okay...
and hurry, because...
Happy birthday.
Son of a bitch!
Where have you been?
Well, we had
a little fight.
I would never lie to
get someone into bed.
You used to tell girls
you were a Kennedy.
( laughing )
Thank you.
Thanks. Ooh...
Thanks.
Well, it's
a little tight, isn't it?
Why didn't you get
a bigger table?
You... you had a big table,
but they made you move.
Shut up, Monica.
Oh, well, I suppose
that Chandler will have
the smoked duck.
And I suppose that
Monica will have
the manipulative
shrew.
I'll give you
another minute.
Where are you going?
He said she wanted
the shrew!
Rachel, come on.
Emma's fine.
You're turning into
an obsessive mother, okay?
You need to stop.
You guys ever hear
the story
about when Ross's mom went
to the beauty salon?
Ah...
You mean
the willy story?
♪ Ha-ha,
they already know it. ♪
You guys, we've been
waiting for you
for a long time.
Maybe you should order.
I already told the
waiter what they want.
Why would you do that?
Chandler, control
your woman!
Okay, well,
everybody has ordered.
I would like to start
the celebration
and make a toast.
To Phoebe...
she dropped her sock.
Oh... what?
No, Emma
dropped her sock.
MONICA:
Mom's here?
I wanted to have lunch
with her today.
She told me
she was out of town.
Wait, Ross, she
still has not noticed
that the baby's sock
is on the ground.
It's a good toast.
Come on, will you please
get her attention?
Oh...
Mommy?
Oh, for God's sake, Judy,
pick up the sock!
Pick up the sock,
I'm sorry.
Was that rude?
D-did my little outburst
blunt the hideousness
that is this evening?
Look, I know you all have
a lot going on
but all I wanted to do
was have dinner
with my friends
on my birthday.
And you were all so late
and you didn't even have
the courtesy to call.
( cell phone ringing )
Well... it's too late now.
Yeah, Pheebs, I don't think
that's us.
Oh.
Well, this is... this is...
this is not over.
Hello?
And what is going on
with you two?
Well, you see,
I'm ovulating.
Oh, yeah.
That's what she says!
But maybe you're not
ovulating at all.
Maybe this is all
just a clever ruse
to get me into bed.
Yeah, Smokey.
That's what it was.
I just can't get enough!
You're not going
to believe this.
She lied.
She tricked me into
having sex with her.
So?
You got to have sex, right?
What's the matter
with me?
Why am I such a girl?
Okay, that was Mike.
Phoebe, honey,
we are so sorry.
You are totally right.
We are here 100%
and we love you
and we are ready
to start your
birthday celebration.
Oh, guys, that means
the world to me.
Okay, I'm going to take off.
What?
Oh, I love you guys, too,
but Mike got off work early.
Wait... wait...
I'm not the kind of girl
that just ditches her friends
to be with her boyfriend.
Know what? I am.
Bye, guys.
Judy... bye.
Oh, thank God.
If Phoebe's gone, can
we please take Emma home?
You know, I think
that's a good idea.
Our baby-sitter
pounded another chardonnay.
Oh, God!
Bye, you guys.
Bye.
See you.
Well, guess
it's just us.
So, I'm probably
still ovulating.
Do you want to give it
another try?
So, you've never had sex
with a Kennedy, have you?
You're going to go
do it now?
We don't have much time.
Once the egg descends
into the fallopian...
Whoa, whoa...
get out of here.
I sincerely hope
the rest of your party
is returning.
No, just me.
All alone.
Dinner for six for one.
Well, you boys
are about to see
something
really special.
How was everything,
sir?
Excellent.
The shrew, in particular,
was exquisite.
Well, I hope
you've got some room left.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday
to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear... ♪
Joey, Joey...
♪ Joey ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you. ♪
Best birthday ever.
Captioned by:
Media Access Group at WGBH